I have bad news for
you. We're going to
meditate, so please get
ready.
Because we will finish
the in Kyoto if we all that long.
We will
start with 100 meditation exercises. Let's
begin. The first exercise is,
can you say, "I was there?"
This isn't called a
livestream meditation, it's called a bribery meditation. Why is it
called a bribery meditation?
If you participate in the
30 30 30 program, 1 dollar a day,
anyone can do that,
right? Then
you will receive
videos as soon as they are
made, right? TH team.
If you don't support us and you don't
contribute 1 dollar a
day, we will send
you the videos by mail in the
US, meaning it will take 5 weeks, you
understand?
So you know,
you
should try to practice
these 100 meditation exercises, okay? And it only costs 1
dollar a day. And if everyone
helps...  This means it can be
free for everyone forever, and
then we won't have to ask
you for anything like $10, it's a waste of
time, right? Are
you ready?
Don't forget to do the wrong thing
in this meditation, it will
last for 100
years because I and
my brothers are
terrible at being silent, like a death knell. Are
you ready?
It's about half an
hour, and the first meditation will be
about 45 minutes, okay? Okay,
let's begin.
Clear your throat, put
a little smile on your face,
and I like to push your lower abdomen,
it will support your back.
Try to relax your forehead.
Relax your
hands, you can hold them
however you like, but make sure
your hands are relaxed and push your
back.
Push your shoulder blades back
a little bit and keep them
balanced. Look straight ahead.  Look straight ahead,
but with your eyelids
closed. So your eyes are
looking towards the horizon, but your eyelids are
shut.
If you look down,
your chin will droop, and
you'll easily fall asleep. So
keep your eyes open and looking
straight ahead.
We'll count
breaths. I know that usually
we count 10 breaths, but
personally, I count 100 breaths,
and that makes
my mind peaceful. So
we'll go to 100 breaths, starting with
exhaling and then
inhaling, and we'll proceed to count 100
breaths. When you start thinking
about the picture or something else,
bring your mind
back and don't let your mind
become irritable or rough.
Treat your mind
gently. Talk to your mind.  My mind tells me to
go back to my
breath, and now we'll begin
by counting our breaths, inhaling and exhaling,
keeping my mouth
soft. I I I I I I I I I I
Now we'll proceed to the
first seven steps of meditation. Think of someone
you truly admire. It could be
someone in your life right
now. It doesn't have to be a
religious person.
It could be anyone you
admire. Someone you wish you were like. It could
be just a quality
you admire, it could be
their whole life, it could be that they have a
special ability to be patient,
or maybe they have the ability to be
kind.
So think of someone
you truly admire
and invite them to meditate with
you. It could be a famous person from the
past. I personally like to invite
Ari n guna or the
Kappa, and it could even be someone
you haven't met
yet.  We are all looking forward to the
day when we can meet the Buddha in person,
and maybe now you
can invite that day to come, right now,
so whether it's the past, present, or
future, it could be someone you truly
admire, or it could be someone
you don't have a particular problem with, for
example, right now when you
feel you're impatient with someone,
you could bring someone—someone
you know is
patient—and invite them to meditate with
you. You can visualize
them level with your forehead,
imagine their size as the size of
your thumb, in mid-
air, right in front of your third eye,
about half a meter
from your head. And personally, I
imagine them as the full size of
a normal person, sitting with
them like two friends.
I enjoy being
friends with
this person, just meditating together as
friends, so make that clear
in your mind.
Think about your own reasons for admiring
them, what qualities they
possess that you want to have
now. Imagine you are
offering a gift to
this person. I like the Samantabhadra offering method;
basically, that day will be filled with a
blue sky, a day when there is no cloud
in the sky, and the sky will be covered with
red roses. The entire
sky will be red roses,
and you offer these flowers to this person
to honor them.
Next, we will perform
repentance for something you have done
in the last two or three days that made you
unhappy, such as being
annoyed with someone or being
envious of someone. Think about any
negative things you have done in the
last two or three days. Of
course, we do a
lot of negative things, right? It
only takes a few seconds to sow a
seed of negativity, but
the goal is...
This third introductory step is that we only think about
one or two negative actions.
Regretting that, and it's a
good practice to tell someone what
happened, it's very healthy. If
we have a habit of telling others about
our weaknesses or
mistakes and being honest with them, then
try to be honest
with yourself and think
about something that's
a bad mental habit
and tell this person
honestly. They are a kind person, they
are a good person, so you
can tell them and you will feel
cleansed. So
think about something you've
done in the last few days and tell
this person, the person you're
meditating with.
Now tell them
something that makes you happy, something
good you did
this morning. We're
meditating together here.  And at the
end of the retreat at Diamond Mountain,
I could
feel that your meditation was quite
good. I could feel that you had
worked very hard this week because
I have meditated with many
people over the years, and I think
you can be proud of
your hard work
this week. And I can tell
you from the meditation part that you
had a good week, you worked
hard, and you can tell
this person about your week and be
happy in a genuine way,
not just
happy that you put in a lot of effort
this week.
The next introductory step is requesting a
lecture. I think most of the lectures
we
receive come from personal interaction
with others. I think that from
those teachers we learn more than
what we usually learn
in class. So today, tomorrow,
or the following days, and especially
when you...  Returning from the retreat, you will
have many interactions with
other people,
and many of us will be
moving around. So, make a
prayer that in the following days, it
won't be
formulaic lectures, but that when we
interact with others, when
we have conversations with
others, make a
prayer that those people will teach
us something, that they might
teach
us something negative,
and we see them behaving in a
bad way, and we might think, "
I hope I won't
see this again, and I
hope I wo
n't do
this myself." So, like a
lecture, a lesson, there will be
good examples and
bad examples, so ask that person,
ask that we receive the
teachings through our
interactions with others.
And the introductory step, Friday, we
are surrounded by...  There are
really good people, and I think sometimes
we get used to it and we're
not aware of them. So
try to think about the good people
in your life, the
good role models in your life. It
could be your friends, it could be
family members, it could be
public figures, it could
be historical figures.
But the people around
us are giving us
examples every day, all
day long, and so they are teaching us. Ask
your teachers to stay in your life.
Pray that you can
recognize your teacher,
then ask them not to leave
you. Ask them to stay with
you.
And after the first six introductory steps,
we will proceed with
our meditation. Today
we will do a very, very
short meditation, and that is the
first of 100 meditations. Dream, and I
think to  This is the first lesson
we're going to discuss, a
very important one.
We
want to become Bodhisattvas in our lives, and
that's a good goal.
If we
can become Bodhisattvas, it
will be wonderful, and we will be
very
happy, and we will make others
happy. So, to be a
Bodhisattva, it's very clear, very
simple. What we have to do is to
become a true Bodhisattva
if we have two
different states of mind, two different attitudes.
First, I'll talk about the second.
We want to
develop an understanding
of where this world comes from, where
all people come from,
and where this world doesn't
come from.
That is the ultimate Bodhicitta, the
second understanding of cause and effect, the understanding
of the spiritual seed, the
understanding...  Knowing that everything
around us comes from us,
from the way we treat
others, and in order to reach that
ultimate second Bodhicitta,
there is a fundamental Bodhicitta that
we need to develop first, and that
is love and
caring. It is the understanding that
others also desire
happiness just like
ourselves. All day long, every
minute of the day, I am always trying to be happy, to be
happy myself, and that is good. It
is wonderful. It is the hope of human
life to be
happy. And our first meditation
today is to
think about someone in
our life, it could be a
friend, a colleague,
anyone, a
family member, or choose one person.
The meditation is very short and very
simple. Do they want happiness?
[music]
in the way that  I want to be happy
all day, so all day I want
lovely things to happen to me every
minute of the day. I hope
lovely things
happen. Now, focus on that other
person
and try to
think if they are like you. Do
they also want to be happy? Do they
hope that every moment, every minute,
they are also happy,
happy every day, every minute? Is
that something inside them? Of course
it's inside me, but
is it
inside them? Are they
hoping that every minute of today,
good things will happen to them
and they will be happy? Just
choose someone and ask yourself if
they want to be happy every minute of today.
We'll be here for a few
minutes. We'll summarize this
meditation; it's short but extremely
powerful, and importantly, it's something
you can practice in the
next few weeks if you want to. Okay, let's...
Let's begin! Let's choose someone...
And now we
'll summarize our meditation.
We've completed our meditation.
We've done a
good deed. The meditation was
short, but the seed and the
mental energy were much stronger than
physical or verbal karma.
So, in just half an
hour, this meditation
planted an extremely powerful seed.
We created
seeds in the center of our minds.
Imagine
those seeds being created in
this meditation. I like to imagine them in the
center of my mind as tiny
golden seeds in
my mind. I like to imagine that I'm
sharing these seeds with
others. I like to
imagine them as Golden Light,
emanating from the
center of my mind and spreading out
through my body like
rays of light surrounding a
Buddha. And then...  It will spread throughout the world
around
me, and I love this Golden Light.
First, it will spread to
my neighbors, then to the
people in the town, and everyone will
be touched by this Golden Light.
I am sharing
my good seeds,
and then it will spread throughout the state
or province where I am currently,
and everyone will get a
taste of the golden light
of my wonderful meditation.
And then I want it to flow out to sea
from the East Coast to the West Coast, then to the
edge of the country, and I like to think that
everyone in the country will receive this
Golden Light. And then
I will spread it across the ocean to
other continents, to other countries, and
then
that light will shine
brightly across the planet and
spread throughout space, crossing
many other planets and the entire universe.
Everyone will be touched by the
Golden Light of
those golden seeds of the meditation I
conducted today, and then everyone will be a
little happier.
Then you can slowly open your eyes
and I like to stretch
I like what you do with your
hands like this, rubbing
your hands My Chinese friend
taught me to do this
Your meditation part is pretty
good I've been helping people meditate
here for about 20
years Yes, we just had a
celebration, right?
And this is one of the
best groups I've ever had I can
feel it I can see it
so I guess I don't know
who leads the meditation here but
that person must have done a
very
good job Do you have any questions?
What time do we stop? 7:15 Do you have
any questions? No, no.
My teacher once said that
you already know everything I'll call
her name and
she looked around like she was
talking about Who is grateful to her, grateful to the
teacher for the meditation, grateful to the teacher for
all the lectures this week and
the question is, it's really hard to
just practice  Focus on one person you
want to help. It's like you're stuck
with one person, and you can fill that
with other people. Is that
okay, sir? I think that's
great. Personally,
I think I'd like to do it
with three people, and I think that's
okay. My advice is that
there's a meditation piece of advice:
it shouldn't be too much. Basically,
you'll get tired or bored,
and it shouldn't be too
busy, so you shouldn't overdo it and you'll lose your focus.
So it's up to you to
challenge your mind. If it's
too simple, you'll get sleepy, and
if it's too complicated, you'll lose
the feeling of helping them.
So I'd say
you need to check
your ability, like a
guitar string, it's not too
tight or too loose, right?
Ben, we need a microphone here.
Thank you, thank you, sir, for the
wonderful meditation. I have a question.
Ask about the way a seed is
sprouting if each moment is
1/65 of a second like this. So,
if each seed that is
sprouting creates me, the teacher, and everyone
in this room, there
is only one seed that creates everything, and
then the next seed, the next one, the
next one, is that understanding
correct? That's a good
question. I'll say it like
this: we have direct experiences,
like when I look into your eyes right now,
and we have
indirect experiences, logical experiences.
When I'm looking at you right now, I
still know there are people around.
I'm not looking at you right now,
but because I'm looking at you,
I have an indirect experience
of
them. I'm still aware that
these people won't sneak
out to eat
breakfast. So, at the same time,
my seed creates a
direct awareness of you. And and there...  Between those,
it creates a perception
of them, and so I'm perceiving
a room full of people, but
actually I'm only looking
directly at you, and I feel the
presence of other people in
the room. So that's called
indirect perception. So I have
direct perception, that seed goes
out, and then I perceive you
directly. And between
those seeds, there are
other indirect seeds that also go out, and then I have
indirect seeds to
feel that I'm on
this planet, and there are many other people and
things like that, things that
are happening in sequence, things that are
happening one by one,
and it's not happening all at
once. A human mind, a
human mind that isn't a Buddha,
can only have that kind of perception.
So, it's really
impossible to perceive you directly all at
once with that thread.  They perceive it,
and it will repeat itself, and
your mind will go back and forth like
that, but the direct and indirect objects
are
created by separate seeds,
and they are happening in sequence, one
after the other, and it's very subtle.
And actually, whether it's
direct or indirect, all the
images that come out of
my mind, in that sense, there's
no difference between
direct and indirect. You
see a picture, an image that
creates you, and then that picture,
by the way, doesn't change. And
that picture is in a
different moment. I have an image,
and then I have
other indirect images, but they are all
images, and they
are all the same images,
okay? And it's very fast, very
fast, and it's not complete. It's
like you're assembling pieces
into a
picture. And you always make a
part, and then
others follow, and you keep
assembling it until you
become a Buddha. Then all the
unfinished parts are gone.
I'm Trac. Hello, teacher. Thank you for
the wonderful lesson. The sentence...  My question
is, if a seed
never touches the plant,
that's the correlation. If
you want this, you do that. So
how can that
touch what you're going to do with
that? So, can you help me understand
this correlation?
A question, or rather, a question, is something that requires
logical thinking. You should have certain questions
after a while. If you don't have
them, it means you're not
thinking at all. So I'm happy that
you ask
such consequential questions. If
you don't think about this question,
then if you have a pen and you're
writing on a piece of
paper, there's a strong feeling of
your ignorance, your misunderstanding.
But incidentally, I don't like to
call it ignorance. I prefer to call it
misunderstanding because ignorance can imply a
lack of
knowledge, but misunderstanding...  It
means you're corrupting the knowledge of
a piece of paper, and you write with a pen,
and it seems like the pen
makes the mark on the paper.
Then you might think, in a misunderstanding, that the pen
makes the mark on the paper, and
that's a mistake. Thinking like that is a
mistake, and it
's very natural for us to think
that way, and then it becomes a
cycle because you think that because the
pen writes on the paper, you
suffer, you are in this realm and
endure suffering. Because you think
that the cause and effect you think
is the ink in the pen making
the mark on the
paper, you think of cause and effect in that way, so
you try to have more pens
in your life, you work to
earn money to have more pens
because you think that's the cause and effect.
But what's really
happening is that the
seeds of the pen are sprouting.
The seeds of the paper sprout, sprout,
sprout, sprout, and the seeds
of writing sprout, sprout, sprout, sprout,
and then your mind creates the
paper, the seeds in your
mind create your hand,
your seeds create the
action that you perform.
You
write, and your mind, the seeds in
your mind, create the mark on the
paper. The pen, without it,
creates the writing; it's very difficult. So you should
appreciate that there's
a cause and effect. When
you write on a piece of paper, there's nothing
between the pen and
the paper. Everything is
your seed, the seed in
your mind, it has placed everything down there, one by one. So, in a
cause-and-effect relationship,
it repeats itself, and it becomes
an unpleasant
cycle. That's what makes
you collect more pens
and
...  Trying to prevent people from having
the pen
and the cycle of reincarnation
will be defeated by
understanding, just like the
case of the seed and the tree.
When the seed is watered and exposed to
sunlight, it becomes
a tree, but it's not the
seed that becomes the tree; it's
all just images in the
mind. The
seed cannot
physically create a tree; it's
impossible because by the time
the tree is there, the seed
has already disappeared. Therefore, they
never touch each other,
never have any contact. The pen tip never
touches the
paper, never.
By definition, a seed cannot come
into contact with a
tree, and a tree can never be
formed from a seed; it's
impossible. It's something else.  It's
happening, and what's happening
is your mind creating
all of that. Why is it like
that, sir? I can
see Angela thinking that way.
Why do we have to consider it
like
sowing a seed and then we have
a tree the next day? Then
there are karmic patterns,
there are patterns where the
seed doesn't create a tree, but
if you don't sow
the seed, the tree won't
grow. That's because those patterns are
rhythmic patterns, and there
are always karmic patterns like that in the
world. Those
patterns hold the truth
most of the time until you reach
a higher level,
okay? Now,
because it's time for me to summon the devil.
I have a lot of pressure to
summon the
devil. By the way, this is
almond milk, okay? You take an
almond mushroom and soak it overnight.
It will swell up and it will...  It will be ready, and
then you drain the water, and then put them
in a blender with some water, and then
add some more water, and then
add some strawberries,
and then make two
glasses. Normally I don't eat
before lunch, but I'll need two
glasses like this, or Bali like
this, and then you won't gain weight. It doesn't
have any sugar or starch
in it,
so the almond and the strawberry do
n't have any sugar or
starch in them, and it's healthy, it's
cheap, and I can save time, and
I don't have to cook. That's a
suggestion.
Thank you,
Teacher, for the second question. But the question is about the physical seed, we can understand that, but what about the spiritual seed? Does it have the same pattern, sir? Regarding the correlation,
how can we fix
that? That's a good question, fundamentally.
I appreciate
Trac's answer about the pine tree and
the  I can understand pine tree seeds.
But
what about mental seeds? And the answer
is correct, it's the same. A
mental seed doesn't create
a mental image, and a
mental image doesn't necessarily come
from the seed. You perceive
it coming from the seed because you're
always doing that. And I'll give
you an example from the Vijñānavāda school,
okay? And this is why
you should attend these classes. Yes, and
they
cost us 2000 years of wisdom, you know.
We've calculated the time
to make it convenient for you, and
it's not convenient for me. If
you continue attending these classes,
all your questions
will be
answered. So in the Vijñānavāda school, they
say that when you look at something
pink, you're actually looking
at something pink in
your subconscious mind. A subconscious mind, you're
looking at the seed.  The seeds bloom within
your own mind; there's no pink
outside of you. Everything is
within your mind—that's the Consciousness-only school,
right? It's not the
Middle Way, but it's useful. Yes, they believe
you're only seeing a part of
your mind. There's
no toad outside,
far away from the teacher's head.
My eyes are here, and the color is
there. There's no such thing. And there's a
big question in the Consciousness-only school:
when I see the
pink color, am I really only
seeing a part of my own mind?
In the Consciousness-only school, I'm only
seeing a part of my mind. And then
a question arises:
why do I feel that it's outside?
Why do I feel that it's
a meter away from me? Why do I have that
feeling of a meter?
Where does that come from? The Consciousness-only school says
you have special seeds.  Separated
from the past, it creates the illusion
of distance from the
outside world. There's a distinct seed
in your mind that creates the
feeling that the color is outside,
and then the big question,
K's question, arises:
when did that state begin?
The answer is, it didn't begin. It did
n't start. So
what does that mean? It means that the
seed will continue
forever. You can't point to the first day
in your past when
you saw the toad outside.
You can't point to that because
there must be a
seed to record it. So,
in your past life,
you saw the toad
outside because in that previous life you had
the seed to see outside, and
it continues like that. And
for Westerners,
they will have a problem with that.
It's so strange. You
know, the seed comes from an
old seed, and the old seed comes from
an even older seed, and that's
strange. And a
true Buddhist would say, "No, you're the
strange one." It's strange when you think that there's
a beginning. That's
strange, just as you think about it and think that there's
a beginning because nothing
comes from nothing.
Nothing comes from nothing. And nothing can be
somewhere in my life
from the time I was running from childhood that
I had to do something, that's
an English song, right? By
the way, it's like
that, it comes from the sign that the
spiritual seed started and it
creates the spiritual image, and then
that sign is the pattern that has
always been like that, and
I'm not avoiding
the question when I say that it has
always been like that, it has always been like
that.  It's like when your mom says to
you, "Why don't you get
any? I never give you candy."